ESTHER MICHAEL MMBAGA

Phone: +255 622 592 645, +255 758 631 012

Email: esthermmbaga95@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVES

To build my career under an organization that helps to grow professional skills. Strategic thinker with superb skills in research, leadership, sales and marketing. Demonstrated integrity, talent for collaborating with senior professionals while maintaining flexibility and willingness to learn.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

2016 - 2019: Bachelor of Arts in Economics (BA); University of Dar Es Salaam

2014 - 2016: Advanced certificate of Secondary Education (ACSEE); Mwanga High School

2010 - 2013: Certificate of Secondary Education (CSEE); Kandoto Science Secondary School

WORK EXPERIENCE

➤ Worked as Business Development Intern at VIVA LEGACY LTD from 07/2019 to 11/2019

Responsibilities

- Support the Internship and Volunteer programme
- Organize event of **Mgahawa Wa Maarifa** programme.
- Support the organization of activities related to the training programme under Mgahawa wa Maarifa
- Organize company meetings, brainstorm sessions and taking minutes
- Support administrative activities.
- Assist in development of training materials in the marketing team
- Participate in preparation of speech writings and Memorandum of Understanding between the company and other companies.
- ➤ Worked as Fundraising Officer at KITE, Dar es Salaam from 09/2018 to 03/2019 Responsibilities
 - Research on potential partners.
 - Prepare fundraising strategies.
 - Support the Project directors in preparations of the budgets.
- ➤ Worked as Business Development Volunteer at Viva Legacy Ltd for 07/2018 to 10/2019

Responsibilities

• Support the finalization of ongoing projects of the company

- Participate in identifying new areas for initiating activities, finalization or expansion of ongoing initiatives
- Identify gaps in company business plan and strategies and recommend concrete actions
- ➤ Worked as Planning and Strategic Intern at TANESCO, Head Office from 07/2017 to 10/2017

Responsibilities

- Support the preparation of Memorandum of understanding of different projects of the company
- Attend discussions of project evaluation
- Support the stuff in inspection of sites to assess validity and feasibility of submitted development plan
- Preparare department official letters

SEMINARS/COURSES

- **2019:** Presentation skills, Interview skills and CV Writing Training at University of Dar es Salaam offered by **KPMG**
- 2018: Project Proposal Writing and FundRaising at University of Dar es Salaam
- 2018: Monitoring and Evaluation at University of Dar es Salaam

SKILLS

• Oral and written communication, Multitasking and prioritization, Reporting capabilities, Event planning, Computer skills, Data entry documentation, Leadership Social Media Management, Communications Management and Time management skill

HOBBIES

• Cooking, Exercising, Travelling, Watching comedy clips.

REFEREE

Emmanuel A. Meela
 Sales and Marketing Executive
 Viva Legacy Ltd.

P.O.BOX 23

Dar es Salaam

Phone: +255 655 088 663

Email: emmanuelmeela@gmail.com

2. Marianus Mgendera

Planning Officer

Department of Strategic Planning

Tanesco Head Office

P.O.BOX 453

Dodoma

Phone: +255 713 032 953

Email:mario.mgendera@gmail.com

3. Dr. Onesmo Selejio

Lecturer

Economics Department

University of Dar es salaam

P.O.BOX 35091

Dar es salaam

Phone: +255 653 460 809 Email: oselejio@gmail.com

DECLARATION/CERTIFICATION

I am undersigned to be the best of my knowledge as this bio data describes my education, my experience and myself.